<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE eduversum>
<eduversum>
	<name>LabPlot</name>
	<seminarix>Engineering;Physics;Mathematics</seminarix>
	<homepage>http://labplot.sourceforge.net/</homepage>
	<desktoppath>/usr/share/doc/ding/examples/ding.desktop</desktoppath>
	<description lang="en">With LabPlot you can create tables with measured values and then display them as function diagrams. It is possible to create 2D and 3D diagrams. A simple editing of the plotted function eases the adjustment to the users requirements.\n\n

	The created function plots can be analysed and evaluated. For that LabPlot offers possibilities which are much more advanced than the capabilities of a spreadsheet editor. With LabPlot the student possesses a valuable tool for evaluating the data they get in school experiments, especially students in higher classes. \n\n

	Some of LabPlot's abilities:[ul]
		[li]Creation, from functions and data files, of surface, polar and ternary plots and pie charts[/li]
		[li]Flexible 3D plot with rotation etc. multiple plots on one work sheet, speed mode for bigger data and data mode to search for single data points[/li]
		[li]Graph cloning and plots deleting/cloning[/li]
		[li]Versatile tables for data manipulation[/li]
		[li]Online plot scaling and editing[/li]
		[li]Evaluation printouts and direct data editing[/li]
		[li]Free or pan zooming. Masking of data points and markers[/li]
		[li]Support for panel-plots[/li]
		[li]Versatile error bar[/li]
	[/ul]
	Function and data analysis:[ul]
		[li]Averaging, smoothing and reduction of data[/li]
		[li]Compression, periodical and time analysis[/li]
		[li]Find spikes[/li]
		[li]Interpolation (Splines, etc.)[/li]
		[li]Varieties[/li]
		[li]Integration[/li]
		[li]Histogram[/li]
		[li]Regression (up-to an order of 10)[/li]
		[li]Non-linear adjustment (also user defined functions with up-to 9 parameters)[/li]
		[li]Fourier-, Laplace, Hankel and Wavelet Transformation (un)folding[/li]
		[li]Image editing[/li]
		[li]Noise, signal filters, and auto / cross-correlation[/li]
		[li]Capability Analysis[/li]
		[li]R for additional functions and descriptive statistics / 1-/2-Sample Tests[/li]
		[li]Support of LaTeX and RichText labels[/li]
	[/ul]
	LabPlot offers import/export filters for more than 80 file formats like ps, eps and pdf. The support for connecting to a data bank like MySql and Postgresql is realised via KexiDB.</description>
</eduversum>